Hyeonmin Lee

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at Seoul National University (SNU), supervised by Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (Network Convergence and Security Lab). My research interests lie in network security and its measurement: Are we using the network correctly and securely? How can we make the network (more) secure?

CONTACT INFORMATION

EMAIL: hmlee@mmlab.snu.ac.kr

ADDRESS: Network Convergence and Security Lab., 5F, Building 301, 1, Gwanak-ro,

Gwanak-gu, Seoul, Republic of Korea

HOMEPAGE: https://hyeonmin-lee.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

NETWORK SECURITY — (especially) DNS security, Mail security SECURITY MEASUREMENT

EDUCATION

MAR 2016 - FEB 2022

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

- Dissertation: "Understanding the DANE Ecosystem in Email: How Is It Deployed and Managed?"
- Supervisor: Prof. Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon

MAR 2011 - FEB 2016 **B.S.**, Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University (SNU), Seoul, Republic of Korea

FALL 2014

Visiting Student, Information Technology, Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

MAY 2019

Visiting Researcher

- AUG 2019

The Center for Cybersecurity, Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, USA

• Topic: Measuring and analyzing the ecosystem of DANE protocol in Email

SPRING 2016

Teaching Assistant

Dept. of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, Korea

• Class: Engineering Frontiers and Leadership 2

PUBLICATIONS

• Under the Hood of DANE Mismanagement in SMTP (to appear)

Hyeonmin Lee, Md. Ishtiaq Ashiq, Moritz Müller, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung

"Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2022

Dataset [https://dane-study.github.io]

• A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email Hyeonmin Lee, Aniketh Gireesh, Roland van Rijswijk-Deij, Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon, Taejoong Chung

In Proceedings of the USENIX Security Symposium (USENIX Security), Boston, United States, Aug 2020

- Dataset [https://dane-study.github.io]

• Development of Cellular Core Network Enabling Network Function Virtualization Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Song

The 28th Joint Conference on Communication and Information (JCCI), Yeosu, Korea, May 2018

· TwinPeaks: An Approach for Certificateless Public Key Distribution for the Internet and Internet of Things

Eunsang Cho, Jeongnyeo Kim, Minkyung Park, Hyeonmin Lee, Chorom Hamm, Soobin Park, Sungmin Sohn, Minhyeok Kang, Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon Elsevier Computer Networks (SCI-E)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Apr 2020 - Present	Research on Traceability for Data Stability on Cloud-edge Lifecycle • Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP) • Role: Researcher / Programmer
MAR 2021 - NOV 2021	Abnormal Detection and Forensic Techniques using IoT Network Traffic Analysis • Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC) • Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / Researcher / Programmer
APR 2016 - DEC 2020	Versatile Network System Architecture for Multi-dimensional Diversity • Supported by Institute for Information and Communication Technology Promotion (IITP) • Role: Project Manager (Lab.) / System Designer / Programmer
FEB 2020 - NOV 2020	Research on GPU Acceleration for Fully Homomorphic Encryption • Supported by Korea Institute of Information Security & Cryptology (KIISC) • Role: Programmer
SEP 2019	Developing High-performance Programming Environments and Computing

- APR 2020

Systems

- Supported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)
- Role: Programmer

AUG 2019 - Nov 2019

Research on Distributed Web Structure and Counterplan

- Supported by Korea Internet and Security Agency (KISA)
- Role: Researcher

SEP 2018 - Nov 2018

Research on Trust and Security Scheme for Interconnection of Heterogeneous Networks

• Supported by Electronics and Telecommunications Research Institute (ETRI)

· Role: Researcher

AUG 2016

Research and Development of Open 5G Reference Model

- FEB 2019
- Supported by Giga KOREA Foundation
- Role: System Designer / Programmer

MAR 2016 - MAY 2016

Content Delivery Framework Using Spatial and Temporal Dynamics in Mobile Networks

- Supported by National Research Foundation of Korea (NRF)
- Role: Programmer

JUL 2015 - DEC 2015

Development of Network Security Acceleration for Next-generation Lowpower SoC

- Supported by Samsung Electronics
- Role: Programmer

PATENTS

- · Network System and Method for Performing Message Security Thereof Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Junghwan Lim, Yoojung Shin
 - Registration No. 1022656110000
 - Republic of Korea, Jun. 10, 2021
- Communication Method Based on Integrated Flat ID and System Ted "Taekyoung" Kwon, Hyunwoo Lee, Myungchul Kwak, Hyeonmin Lee, Dongjun Lee, Hyunchul Oh
 - Registration No. 1020231150000
 - Republic of Korea, Sep. 11, 2019

TALKS & PRESENTATIONS

- Aug 2020, USENIX Security, Online, "A Longitudinal and Comprehensive Study of the DANE Ecosystem in Email"
 - Slides [https://www.usenix.org/system/files/sec20 slides lee-hyeonmin.pdf]
 - Video [https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=amklb5UqBNE&ab channel=USENIX]

Miscellaneous

MAR 2019

Expert Research Personnel (military service)

- FEB 2022

Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

The expert research personnel system is a form of alternative military service in Republic of Korea, where the military service is fulfilled by conducting research at a domestic university or company for three years. I had not been involved in any military research project throughout the service.

REFERENCES

Taekyoung "Ted" Kwon (tkkwon@snu.ac.kr)

• Professor, Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University, Seoul, Republic of Korea

Taejoong (Tijay) Chung (tijay@vt.edu)

· Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA, United States